Koumba KEITA

Frontend engineer

koumbakeita.com

Toronto, Ontario koumbakeita47@gmail.com +1 647-977-4027 linkedin.com/in/koumba-keita-8635b9137

SUMMARY

Web developer with a graphic design background, boasting four years of coding experience. Transitioned successfully from graphic design, bringing a creative edge to development projects. Holds a Canadian work permit and eager to gain international experience. Available to start in March 2024.

EDUCATION

Bachelor degree in Web development Web@cademie by EPITECH – Kremlin-Bicêtre, France	Nov. 2019 - Nov. 2021
Preparatory school in Illustration Corvisart High School – Paris, France	Oct. 2019 - Jul. 2021
Associate degree in Graphic Design Garamont High School – Colombes, France	Sept. 2016 - Jul. 2018
Preparatory school in Applied Arts Sèvres High School – Sèvres, France	Sept. 2015 - Jul. 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

Vade - Full remote

- Participating to building up the design system of the company as the main developer of the project based on the Figma prototypes provided by the UX/UI team.
- Developing the components of the design system using Vue 3, Tailwind, Typescript, and Storybook.
- Documenting each component in Supernova to ensure seamless integration and future scalability of the system.

Frontend Engineer

Leavy - Paris, France

Dec. 2021 - Mar. 2023

Mar. 2023 - Present

- Designing and coding the internal admin service to manage the registered users, accommodation listings and the payouts schedule using Figma, Vue & TypeScript
- Developing the user webapp, closely following the Figma prototypes provided by the UX/UI team, to manage the user signup flow, accommodation descriptions and reservations using Vue.js and TypeScript

- Collaborating closely with the backend team to integrate the backend API
- Designing and building up the email templates (for registration, forgot password, bookings...) using Mailjet and integrating them to the app flow on different events

Full-stack Developer & Graphic Designer (internship)

Sept. 2020 - Nov. 2021

OSP - Neuilly-sur-Seine, France

- Developing the domiciliation website of the company, for submitting and generating online contracts using Laravel Vue & MySQL.
- Creating an internal admin dashboard to upload the scans of the client's mails and to send alerts when they receive packages using Laravel Vue & MySQL
- Designing the brand identity and the logo of Ospdom using Illustrator InDesign & After Effects

COMPETENCES

PROGRAMMING

- HTML
- Vue
- ¡Query

- CSS
- React JS
- PHP

- JavaScript
- LaravelSymfony
- GitFirebase

- TailwindSass
- TypeScript
- Mailjet

DESIGN / ILLUSTRATION

- Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- InDesign
- Figma
- Illustrator
- Canva
- After Effects
- Procreate

SOFT SKILLS

Teamwork

- Creativity
- Positive attitude

LANGUAGES

French: Native English: Fluent

HOBBIES

- Drawing
- Painting
- · Graphic design
- Reading
- Cooking